<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Craig Rosie</title>
    <link>https://craigrosie.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Craig Rosie</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://craigrosie.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>(I)Python Startup Scripts</title>
      <link>https://craigrosie.github.io/posts/python-startup-scripts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://craigrosie.github.io/posts/python-startup-scripts/</guid>
      <description>Python IPython But why?  Basic Imports Custom Functions Taking it to the Next Level    Are you a frequent user of Python or IPython interactive shells? Do you find yourself constantly reimporting the same libraries (I&amp;rsquo;m looking at you from pprint import pprint 👀), or redefining the same helper functions?
This post will describe how to set up some scripts that will be automatically executed when you run python or ipython in your terminal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Command Line Browser Shortcuts - Git</title>
      <link>https://craigrosie.github.io/posts/command-line-browser-shortcuts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://craigrosie.github.io/posts/command-line-browser-shortcuts/</guid>
      <description>The other day I was making some maintenance changes across a bunch of different git repos, and for each change I need to open a Merge Request in GitLab. This meant that I needed to browse to each repo&amp;rsquo;s page in GitLab, which is not too bad if the git hosting software you&amp;rsquo;re using is speedy, however our instance of GitLab was&amp;hellip; not.
After sitting watching the GitLab loading bar for seconds at a time, I thought &amp;ldquo;there must be a better way to do this from the command line&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beware ujson.dumps() Precision</title>
      <link>https://craigrosie.github.io/posts/beware-ujson-dumps-precision/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://craigrosie.github.io/posts/beware-ujson-dumps-precision/</guid>
      <description>Are you using u(ltra)json over the standard library&amp;rsquo;s json module due to the performance benefits?
Until recently, I was too, but then I discovered that usjon.dumps() loses a lot of &amp;ldquo;precision&amp;rdquo; in floats compared to json.dumps():
&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; ujson.dumps(1.3959197885670265) &amp;#39;1.3959197886&amp;#39; &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; json.dumps(1.3959197885670265) &amp;#39;1.3959197885670265&amp;#39; You might now be thinking to yourself, doesn&amp;rsquo;t usjon.dumps() take a double_precisionparameter that allows you to control the &amp;ldquo;maximum digit precision of doubles&amp;rdquo;?
Well, you would be correct. Let&amp;rsquo;s try it:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Essential Command Line Tools: xmllint</title>
      <link>https://craigrosie.github.io/posts/essential-command-line-tools-xmllint/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://craigrosie.github.io/posts/essential-command-line-tools-xmllint/</guid>
      <description>I currently spend a lot of my time at the command line, so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d start a series on tools that are essential to my workflow. Some of these will be well known tools, and others less so, but hopefully there&amp;rsquo;s something useful for everyone!
xmllint What is it? xmllint is a command line XML tool.
How do I get it? It&amp;rsquo;s built in to MacOS (ships with the libxml2 package) 🎉</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding a progress bar to your Python script</title>
      <link>https://craigrosie.github.io/posts/adding-a-progress-bar-to-python-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://craigrosie.github.io/posts/adding-a-progress-bar-to-python-script/</guid>
      <description>The problem? You&amp;rsquo;re writing a Python script which carries out some tasks in a loop. Maybe you&amp;rsquo;re processing data in a bunch of files, or scraping a list of websites. Whatever it is, the task takes anything from a few seconds to a few minutes to complete. Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t it be great if you could visualise progress (in the command line no less!) easily, and without some ugly print() statements in your code?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting PyCharm to work with pyenv local</title>
      <link>https://craigrosie.github.io/posts/pycharm-with-pyenv/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://craigrosie.github.io/posts/pycharm-with-pyenv/</guid>
      <description>I write the majority of my code in Sublime Text, favouring it over a full blown IDE like PyCharm or Eclipse. However, I cannot argue with the debugging abilities that an IDE provides.
Recently I tried to use PyCharm&amp;rsquo;s debugging functionality, and although when adding the folder as a PyCharm project and specifying the relevant pyenv virtualenv1Python path (see image below), PyCharm just could not seem to find it.
After a bit of prodding and poking, I discovered that in the main PyCharm preferences, the Project Interpreter was still set to the pyenv global Python version, like so:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up pyenv and pyenv-virtualenv</title>
      <link>https://craigrosie.github.io/posts/setting-up-pyenv-virtualenv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://craigrosie.github.io/posts/setting-up-pyenv-virtualenv/</guid>
      <description>I have a confession to make; I&amp;rsquo;ve only been using Python virtualenvs for about 6 months (I&amp;rsquo;ve been working with Python for ~2 years now).
To be honest, by the time I&amp;rsquo;d been introduced to them, I&amp;rsquo;d already royally screwed up my default Python&amp;rsquo;s site-packages, and I was developing on Windows, so virtualenvs just seemed like a lot of hassle. Anyway, everything mostly seemed to sort of work, so why change anything, right?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Copy to the clipboard in Vim</title>
      <link>https://craigrosie.github.io/posts/vim-copy-to-clipboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://craigrosie.github.io/posts/vim-copy-to-clipboard/</guid>
      <description>I love using Vim for making quick changes to files when I&amp;rsquo;m working on the command line. I even use the Vim keyboard shortcuts in Sublime Text, and these days I struggle to use any text editor that does not allow me to enable Vim key bindings.
Recently, I found myself needing to copy text to the clipboard from a text file that I had open in Vim. I am pretty ashamed to say that I didn&amp;rsquo;t think there&amp;rsquo;d be a key combination to allow me to do this, so I always resorted to using the mouse.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
