<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>vim on Craig Rosie</title>
    <link>https://craigrosie.github.io/tags/vim/</link>
    <description>Recent content in vim on Craig Rosie</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://craigrosie.github.io/tags/vim/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Render Github Markdown From Vim</title>
      <link>https://craigrosie.github.io/posts/render-github-markdown-from-vim/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://craigrosie.github.io/posts/render-github-markdown-from-vim/</guid>
      <description>If you work in tech, chances are that you&amp;rsquo;ve had to write some Markdown documents, and it is also reasonably likely that you&amp;rsquo;ve had to upload those Markdown documents to Github.
Github (and other git-hosting sites) provide quite a decent in-browser Markdown editor, but for anything other than the smallest of changes, it can be quicker to use your day-to-day code editor.
If you use vim, you might be wondering how you can preview the Markdown you&amp;rsquo;re writing to see exactly what it will look like once you&amp;rsquo;ve committed and pushed to Github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Copy to the clipboard in Vim</title>
      <link>https://craigrosie.github.io/posts/vim-copy-to-clipboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://craigrosie.github.io/posts/vim-copy-to-clipboard/</guid>
      <description>I love using Vim for making quick changes to files when I&amp;rsquo;m working on the command line. I even use the Vim keyboard shortcuts in Sublime Text, and these days I struggle to use any text editor that does not allow me to enable Vim key bindings.
Recently, I found myself needing to copy text to the clipboard from a text file that I had open in Vim. I am pretty ashamed to say that I didn&amp;rsquo;t think there&amp;rsquo;d be a key combination to allow me to do this, so I always resorted to using the mouse.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>